<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The schedule containing the draught of the charter mentioned in the commission to which it is annexed and whereunto the same hath reference</title>
            <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1689-1694 : William and Mary)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1694</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 74 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A62329</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S848</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R214945</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99826986</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99826986</idno>
            <idno type="VID">31398</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A62329)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 31398)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1845:27)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The schedule containing the draught of the charter mentioned in the commission to which it is annexed and whereunto the same hath reference</title>
                  <author>England and Wales. Sovereign (1689-1694 : William and Mary)</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>15, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1694]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Responding to anno 5-6, William and Mary, cap. 20.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Goldsmiths' Library, University of London.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Excise tax --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  William and Mary, 1689-1702 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-06</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:31398:1"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:31398:1"/>
            <head>The Schedule containing the Draught of the Charter mentioned in the Commiſſion to which it is Annexed and whereunto the ſame hath Reference.</head>
            <opener>
               <signed>
                  <hi>WILLIAM</hi> and <hi>MARY,</hi> By the Grace of GOD, of <hi>England, Scotland, France,</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> King and Queen, Defenders of the Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </signed>
               <salute>To all to whom theſe Preſents ſhall come, Greeting:</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>Whereas, in,<note place="margin">Recital of the Act.</note> and by a certain Act lately made in Parliament, (Entituled, <hi>An Act for Granting to Their Majeſties ſeveral Rates and Duties upon Tunnage of Ships and Veſſels, and upon Beer, Ale, and other Liquors, for ſecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring certain Recompences and Advantages in the ſaid Act mentioned, to ſuch Perſons as ſhall voluntarily Advance the Sum of Fifteen Hundred Thouſand Pounds towards carrying on the War againſt</hi> France) It is (amongſt other Things) Enacted, That for and during the Term of Four Years, Commencing from the firſt day of <hi>June,</hi> in the year of Our Lord One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety and Four, there ſhould be through<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out the Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> Dominion of <hi>Wales,</hi> and Town of <hi>Berwick upon Tweed,</hi> Raiſed, Levied, Collected, and paid for, and upon the Tonnage of all Ships and Veſſels, wherein at any time or times, and for every time during the ſaid Term of Four Years, there ſhould be Imported any Goods or Merchandizes into this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of <hi>England,</hi> Dominion of <hi>Wales,</hi> or Town of <hi>Berwick upon Tweed,</hi> from any Parts, Places, or Countries in the ſaid Act mention'd; or wherein, during the ſaid Term there ſhould be carried Coaſtwiſe, from any Port, Member, or Creek, in the Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> Dominion of <hi>Wales,</hi> or Town of <hi>Berwick upon Tweed,</hi> unto any other Port, Creek, or Member, within the ſame Kingdom, Dominion. Port, or Town, the ſeveral and reſpective Rates, Impoſitions, Duties, and Sums of Money in the ſaid Act mentioned; And that from and after the Seventeenth day of <hi>May,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year of Our Lord One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety and Seven, there ſhall be throughout the ſaid Kingdom of <hi>England,</hi> Dominion of <hi>Wales,</hi> and Town of <hi>Ber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wick upon Tweed,</hi> Raiſed, Levied, Collected, and Paid unto Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, for Beer, Ale, Syder, and other Liquors, certain Additional Rates or Duties of Exciſe in the ſaid Act particularly Expreſſed; And that Weekly, (to wit) on <hi>Wedneſday</hi> in every Week, (if it be not an Holiday) and if it be, then the next day after that is not an Holiday: All and every the Monies ariſing by the Rates and Duties by the ſaid Act Granted, ſhould be paid into the Receipt of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> under certain Penalties therein mentioned; And that yearly, and every year, reckoning the firſt year to begin from the Firſt day of <hi>June,</hi> in the year of Our Lord One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Four, the full Sum of One Hundred and Forty Thouſand Pounds, by, or out of the Monies to ariſe by the ſaid ſeveral Duties, upon the Tunnage of Ships and Veſſels, and by the ſaid Rates and Duties of Exciſe, or any of them, and to be brought into the Receipt of the <hi>Exchequer</hi> by Weekly Payments, as aforeſaid, (in caſe the ſaid Weekly Payments ſhall extend thereunto) ſhould be the whole and entire yearly Fund; And in caſe the ſaid Weekly Payments ſhould not amount to One Hundred and Forty Thouſand Pounds <hi>per Annum,</hi> then the ſaid Weekly Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies, or Payments, ſo far as the ſame will extend, ſhould be part of the yearly Fund, for and towards the Anſwering and Paying of the ſeveral Annuities, and other Pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſes in the ſaid Act expreſſed; And in Caſe the ſaid Duties upon the Tunnage of Ships and Veſſels, and the ſaid Rates and Duties of Exciſe, or any of them, ſhould at any time or times appear to be ſo deficient or low in the produce of the ſame, as that within any one year to be reckoned as aforeſaid, the Weekly Payments up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the ſaid Rates or Duties, or any of them, ſhall not amount to ſo much as One Hundred and Forty Thouſands Pounds, or to ſo much as ſhall be ſufficient to Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge and Satisfie the ſaid ſeveral and reſpective Annuities, and other Benefits, or Advantages, by the ſaid Act intended or appointed to be paid within, or for the
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:31398:2"/>ſame year reſpectively; That then, and ſo often, and in every ſuch Caſe, the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners of Our Treaſury, and the Under-Treaſurer of the <hi>Exchequer</hi> now being, and the Treaſurer, and Under-Treaſurer of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> or Commiſſioners of the Treaſury for the time being are thereby ſtrictly Injoyned and Required, by Virtue of the ſaid Act, and without any further or other Warrant to be Sued for, had, or obtained from Us, Our Heirs or Succeſſors in this behalf, to cauſe every ſuch De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficiency to be made good, by applying, iſſuing, or paying ſo much of any Treaſure or Revenue, belonging, or to belong unto Us, Our Heirs or Succeſſors, (not being Appropriated to any particular Uſe or Uſes, by any Act or Acts of Parliament) to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the Diſcharging or Paying of the ſaid Annuities, or other Benefits or Advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tages appointed to be paid by the ſaid Act, as together with the Moneys, which ſhall have been brought into the ſaid Receipt, of, or for, the ſaid ſeveral Rates or Duties ſhall be ſufficient to pay off, and Diſcharge, and ſhall compleatly pay off and Diſcharge all the Moneys which within the ſame year reſpectively ſhall be grown due, or ought to be paid upon the ſaid Annuities, or other Benefits or Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantages, according to the true intent and meaning of the ſaid Act: And it is there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by further Enacted, That it ſhould and might be Lawful, to, and for Us, by Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> to Authorize and Appoint any number of Perſons, to Take and Receive all ſuch voluntary Subſcriptions as ſhould be made, on, or before the Firſt day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> in the year of Our Lord One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety Four, by any Perſon or Perſons, Natives or Foreigners, Bodies Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>litick or Corporate, for, and towards the Raiſing and Paying into the Receipt of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> the Sum of Twelve Hundred Thouſand Pounds, part of the Sum of Fifteen Hundred Thouſand Pounds in the ſaid Act mentioned; And that the yearly Sum of One Hundred Thouſand Pounds, part of the ſaid yearly Sum of One Hundred and Forty Thouſand Pounds, ariſing by, and out of the Duties and Impoſitions afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentioned, ſhould be applied, iſſued and directed, and is thereby appropriated to the Uſe and Advantage of ſuch Perſon and Perſons, Bodies Politick and Corporate, as ſhould make ſuch voluntary Subſcriptions and Payments, their Heirs, Succeſſors or Aſſigns; And that each Weekly, or other Payment, ariſing by and out of the ſaid Duties and Impoſitions, ſhould by the Auditor of the Receipt of <hi>Exchequer,</hi> from time to time, as the ſame ſhall be paid in, be ſeparated and divided into five ſeventh parts, and two ſeventh parts; And that the ſaid five ſeventh parts of the ſaid ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Payments, ariſing by, and out of the Duties and Impoſitions aforeſaid, and ſo ſet apart, ſhall be Appropriated for, and towards the Payment and Satisfaction of the ſaid yearly Sum of One Hundred Thouſand Pounds, and ſhall from time to time be iſſued and paid, as the ſame ſhall come into the ſaid Receipt of <hi>Exchequer,</hi> to the Uſes and Advantages of ſuch Subſcribers and Contributors, their Heirs, Succeſſors or Aſſigns, as ſhould Subſcribe and Contribute, for, and towards the raiſing and paying into the ſaid Receipt of <hi>Exchequer,</hi> the ſaid Sum of Twelve Hundred Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Pounds; And that it ſhould and might be lawful for Us, by Letters Patents under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> to limit, direct, and appoint, how, and in what manner and proportions, and under what Rules and Directions the ſaid Sum of Twelve Hundred Thouſand Pounds, part of the ſaid Sum of Fifteen Hundred Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Pounds, and the ſaid yearly Sum of One Hundred Thouſand Pounds, part of the ſaid yearly Sum of One Hundred and Forty Thouſand Pounds, and every or any Part or Proportion thereof, may be Aſſignable or Transferrable, Aſſigned or Transferred, to ſuch Perſon or Perſons only as ſhall freely and voluntarily accept of the ſame, and not otherwiſe; And to Incorporate all and every ſuch Subſcribers and Contributors, their Heirs, Succeſſors, or Aſſignees, to be one Body Corporate and Politick, by the Name of <hi>The Governor and Company of the Bank of England,</hi> to have perpetual Succeſſion, and with ſuch Priviledges and Powers, and to be under ſuch Rules as are therein mentioned, ſubject nevertheleſs to a certain Proviſo, or Condition of Redemption in the ſaid Act contained; And it is thereby further Ena<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted, That in Caſe the ſaid whole Sum of Twelve Hundred Thouſands ſhall not be advanced and paid into the Receipt of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> before the firſt day of <hi>Ja<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuary,</hi> which ſhall be in the year of Our Lord One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety and Four, that then the Subſcribers and Contributors, for, and towards the Raiſing and Paying of the ſaid Sum of Twelve Hundred Thouſands Pounds, part of the ſaid Sum of Fifteen Hundred Thouſand Pounds, their Heirs, Succeſſors and Aſſignees, ſhall only have and receive ſo much, and ſuch part and proportion to the ſaid Sum
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:31398:2"/>and Sums ſo reſpectively paid and advanced, as ſhall be after the rate of eight Pounds <hi>per Cent. per Annum;</hi> And for the better and more ſpeedy payment of the ſaid yearly Sum of One Hundred Thouſand Pounds, the Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury, and the Under-Treaſurer of the <hi>Exchequer</hi> now being; and the High-Treaſurer and Under-Treaſurer, or Commiſſioners of the Treaſury for the time being, are thereby ſtrictly Enjoyned and Required, by Virtue of the ſaid Act, and without any further or other Warrant to be Sued for, had, or obtained from Us, Our Heirs or Succeſſors, to di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rect their Warrants yearly for the payment of the ſaid yearly Sum of One hundred thouſand Pounds to the Contributors of the ſaid Sum of Twelve hundred thouſand Pounds, in ſuch Manner and Proportions as are therein Directed and Appointed; And the Auditor of the Receipt of Our <hi>Exchequer,</hi> and all other Officers of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> now, and for the time being, are thereby Directed and Enjoyned to iſſue the ſaid Moneys, ſo ſet a-part for the Uſes afore-mentioned, from time to time, without any Fee or Reward, and under ſuch Penalties as are by the ſaid Act to be inflicted. And in the ſaid Act is contained a Proviſo, That in caſe the whole Sum of Twelve hundred thouſand Pounds, or a Moity thereof, ſhould not be Subſcribed on or before the Firſt day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> One thouſand ſix hundred ninety four aforeſaid, that then the Powers and Authorities in the ſaid Act for Erecting a Corporation as aforeſaid, ſhould ceaſe and determine. And it is further Enacted, That any Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys payable to any Perſon or Perſons upon, or by Virtue of the ſaid Act, ſhall not be Charged or Chargeable with any Rates, Duties, or Impoſitions whatſoever, as in and by the ſaid Act of Parliament (amongſt divers other Matters and Things therein contained, relation being thereunto had) may more fully appear.</p>
            <p>And whereas, in purſuance of the ſaid Act,<note place="margin">Recital of the Commiſſion.</note> We did by Our Commiſſion or Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters Patents under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing Date at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> the Fifteenth day of <hi>June</hi> now laſt paſt, Nominate, Conſtitute, Authorize, and Appoint Sir <hi>William Aſhurſt,</hi> Knight, Mayor of our City of <hi>London;</hi> Sir <hi>John Cope,</hi> Sir <hi>Thomas Littleton,</hi> Sir <hi>John Shaw,</hi> Sir <hi>Walter Young,</hi> Sir <hi>Joſiah Child,</hi>
               <note place="margin">Names of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners.</note> Sir <hi>John Morden,</hi> Sir <hi>William Cooper,</hi> Sir <hi>John Huband,</hi> Sir <hi>Francis Lawly,</hi> Baronets; Sir <hi>Robert Cotton</hi> of <hi>Cambridgeſhire,</hi> Knight, Sir <hi>Robert Clayton,</hi> Sir <hi>Patience Ward,</hi> Sir <hi>James Houblon,</hi> Sir <hi>John Houblon,</hi> Sir <hi>Edward Clearke,</hi> Sir <hi>Richard Levett,</hi> Sir <hi>William Gore,</hi> Sir <hi>William Hedges,</hi> Sir <hi>Thomas Abney,</hi> Aldermen of our City of London; Sir <hi>Charles Caeſar,</hi> Sir <hi>Edward Abney,</hi> Sir <hi>Benjamin Newland,</hi> Sir <hi>John Werden,</hi> Sir <hi>John Bucknall,</hi> Sir <hi>Peter Vandeput,</hi> Sir <hi>William Cranmer,</hi> Sir <hi>Henry Furnes,</hi> Sir <hi>Iſaac Rebow,</hi> Sir <hi>William Scawen,</hi> Sir <hi>John Buckworth,</hi> Sir <hi>John Eyles,</hi> Sir <hi>John Chardin,</hi> Knights; <hi>Mordecai Abbot, George Pitt, Thomas Pitt,</hi> Maſter in <hi>Chancery; William Dorington, Brooke Bridges, Robert Briſtow, Charles Fox, Thomas Felton, James Chadwick,</hi> Dr. <hi>George Oxenden, Charles Williams, Henry Corniſh, Edward Clark,</hi> Colonel <hi>Henry Cornwall, William Gulſton, Charles Godolphin,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>John Germain, Charles Godfrey, Thomas Howard, Thomas Hall, Nathaniel Herne, Robert Henly, John Jefferies, John Knight, Richard Hutchinſon, Charles Duncombe, Joſeph Haskyn Styles, Francis Scobell, John Morrice, Thomas Mawle, Thomas Papillon, Phillip Papillon, Francis Parry, William Palmes,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Nathaniel Tench, Francis Tyſſen, Samuel Travers, Thomas Weſtern,</hi> Senior; <hi>Samuel Weſterne. Thomas Weſterne,</hi> Junior; <hi>Robert Atwood, Peter Ducane, William Desboverie, John Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boiſe, Peter Delmee, William Diſher, James Dufay, Francis Eyles, Barrington Eaton, James Bateman, William Bridges,</hi> Linnen-Draper; <hi>Samuel Bulteele, Charles Ball,</hi> Eſquires; <hi>Bartholomew Burton,</hi> Gent. <hi>Bartholomew Beale, George Bodington, Peter Burrell, John Bellamy,</hi> Scrivener, <hi>David Becceler, William Fawkner, James Fowlis, Samuel Foot,</hi> Junior; <hi>Bartholomew Fillingham, John Carter, Gerrard Conyers, Richard Carey, John Cooke,</hi> Lin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nen-Draper; <hi>Charles Chamberlaine, William Coward, Francis Gosfright, Thomas Goddard, Michael Godfrey, Peter Godfrey, Francis Gell, Lewis Gervaice, Thomas Guy, Peter Houblon,</hi> Junior; <hi>Abraham Houblon, Gilbert Heathcot, Samuel Heathcot, Edmund Harriſon, Matthew Humberſton,</hi> Dr. <hi>Thomas Hobbs, Daniel Hayes, Edward Haiſtwell, Thomas Hancock, Robert Raworth, Samuel Rawſterne, George Richards, Hillary Renew, Benjamin Rookeby, Matthew Raper, Theodore Janſen, Walter Kent, William Knight, John Kendrick, John Lordell, Robert Lyddall, Samuel Lock, John Lloyd, William Lowndes, Timothy Lannoy, James La Bretoniere, Thomas Scawen, Obediah Sedg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wick, Samuel Sheppard, John Smith,</hi> Silkman; <hi>Robert Mitchel, John Nicholſon, Foot Onſlow, Samuel Ongley, William Paterſon, Peter Paggen, Arthur Shallet, Stephen Seignoret, John Sherbrook, Humphry Sympſon, Henry Spencer, John Smith</hi> in <hi>Beauford-Buildings; Maximi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lian Weſtern, Joſeph Tyley, Francis Tierens, Henry Tate, Jaſper Vandebuſh, Gerrard Van<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>huitſen, John Ward, John Woolfe, Robert Whittingham, Richard Mulys, Robert Yate, John
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:31398:3"/>Ellis, Thomas Edwards, James Vernon, William Aſh, Edward Herris, Hugh Squire, Edward Littleton, Richard Cheyney, John Holland, William Sedgwick, William Jarret, John Shipman,</hi> and <hi>Conſtantine Vernatty,</hi> Eſquires, to be Our Commiſſioners to Take and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive all ſuch Voluntary Subſcriptions as ſhould be made on or before the ſaid Firſt day of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> in the Year of Our Lord One thouſand ſix hundred ninety four, by any Perſon or Perſons, Natives or Foreigners, or by, or for any Body Politick or Corporate, for, or towards the raiſing and paying the ſaid Sum of Twelve hundred thouſand Pounds, part of the ſaid Sum of Fifteen hundred thouſand Pounds in the ſaid Act mentioned, with Power and Direction to them, or ſuch, or ſo many of them as are thereby Authorized and Appointed, to take ſuch Subſcriptions, and to do and perform ſuch Matters and Things in Relation thereunto as are thereby Enjoyned.</p>
            <p>And We did in and by the ſame Promiſe and Declare, That in Caſe the whole Sum of Twelve hundred thouſand Pounds, or the Moiety, or any greater part thereof, ſhould be Subſcribed on the ſaid Act, or in purſuance of the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion, on or before the ſaid Firſt day of <hi>Auguſt</hi> then next enſuing, that then We, Our Heirs or Succeſſors, ſhould and would immediately after the ſaid Firſt day of <hi>Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guſt,</hi> or ſo ſoon as Twelve hundred thouſand Pounds ſhould be Subſcribed, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, which of them ſhould firſt happen, Grant and Make forth Our Royal Charter or Letters Patents under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> and thereby Incorporate all and every ſuch Subſcribers and Contributors who ſhould be then living, and who ſhould not have Aſſigned their Intereſt in their ſaid Subſcriptions; And in Caſe any of them ſhould be Dead, the Heirs of ſuch Subſcribers; And in Caſe any of the ſaid Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribers ſhould have Aſſigned their Intereſt in their ſaid Subſcriptions, in all ſuch Caſes the Aſſignees of ſuch Subſcribers to be one Body Corporate and Politique by the Name of <hi>The Governor and Company of the Bank of England,</hi> with ſuch Powers, Capacities, Priviledges, Benefits, Liberties and Advantages, and under and ſubject to ſuch Rules, Reſtrictions, Power of Redemption, Proviſoes, Limitations, and Clauſes as are therein mentioned, or referred unto; And We did thereby for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors Declare, Limit, Direct, and Appoint, That the whole Sum or Amount of all and every the Sum and Sums of Money as ſhould be Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed and Paid as aforeſaid, ſhould be, and be Called, Accepted, Eſteemed, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puted, and Taken a Common, Capital, and Principal Stock; And all and every Perſon and Perſons, his, her, and their Heirs, Succeſſors, and Aſſigns, according, and in proportion to the Sum or Sums of Money by him, her, or them reſpectively Subſcribed and Paid thereunto, ſhould have and be deemed to have an Intereſt or Share in the ſaid Principal Stock, and of and in the Yearly Fund granted by the ſaid Act of Parliament, as aforeſaid; And that ſuch Intereſt or Share, or any part thereof, ſhould be Aſſignable and Transferrable, and ſhould and might be Aſſigned and Transferred by any Perſon or Perſons Intituled thereunto, to any other Perſon or Perſons, and ſo over as fully and effectually as any other Intereſt whatſoever is by Law Aſſignable, ſo as ſuch Aſſignments or Transferrances ſhould be made in Writing, and be Entred or Regiſtred in ſuch manner as is hereafter mentioned: That to ſay, all Aſſignments or Transferrances which ſhould be made on or before the ſaid Firſt day of <hi>Auguſt</hi> next enſuing, or the full and compleat Subſcribing of the ſaid 1200000 <hi>l.</hi> which ſhould firſt happen, and before the granting of theſe Preſents were thereby directed to be Entred or Regiſtred in the Office of the Auditor of the Receipt of Our <hi>Exchequer,</hi> within 6 days after the making of the ſaid reſpective Aſſignments; And all Aſſignments or Transferrances which ſhould be made after the Granting of this Our Charter of Incorporation ſhould be Made, Entred, and Regiſtred in ſuch Form as ſhould be preſcribed in theſe Preſents. And in the ſaid Commiſſion are contained ſeveral other Powers, Directions, Agreements, Clauſes, Matters and Things, as in and by the ſame, relation being thereunto had, more fully and at large appears.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Recital of the Duplicates tranſmitted into the Audi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors Office.</note>And whereas it appears by Duplicates tranſmitted into the Office of the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditor of the Receipt of Our <hi>Exchequer,</hi> under the Hands and Seals of Five or more of Our ſaid Commiſſioners, being a competent and ſufficient number for that pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe, and made in purſuance of Our Directions in the ſaid Commiſſion contained, that ſeveral Sums amounting in the whole to the Sum of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> have been Subſcribed, and the firſt Fourth part thereof paid to Our ſaid Commiſſioners, or ſome of them, purſuant to the ſaid Act of Parliament, on or be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:31398:3"/>the <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> day <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> laſt paſt by <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Recital of the Aſſignments.</note>And whereas it alſo appears by the Entries of ſeveral Aſſignments made and entred in the ſaid Office of the Auditor of the Receipt of Our <hi>Exchequer,</hi> purſuant to the Directions contained in Our ſaid Commiſſion, That <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> Are by mean Aſſignment or Aſſignments ſeverally and reſpectively Intituled to the Benefits of the Subſcriptions which were ſeverally made by the ſaid <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap>
            </p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Incorporating Clauſe.</note>Now, know ye, That We being deſirous to promote the Publick Good and Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefit of Our People (which in theſe Preſents are chiefly deſigned and intended) as well as the Profit and Advantage of all ſuch as have Subſcribed and Contributed according to the ſaid Act of Parliament, and Our ſaid Commiſſion thereupon iſſued, their Heirs, Succeſſors, and Aſſigns reſpectively, and in purſuance as well of the Powers and Clauſes for this purpoſe contained in the ſaid Act of Parliament, as of Our Gracious Promiſe and Declaration made in, or by Our ſaid Commiſſion, or Letters Patents under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> whereby the Subſcriptions and Contributions on the ſaid Act have been promoted or encouraged; And by Vertue of Our Prerogative Royal, and likewiſe of Our Eſpecial Grace, Certain Know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge, and Meer Motion, have Given, Granted, Made, Ordained, Conſtituted, Declared, Appointed, and Eſtabliſhed, and by theſe Preſents for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, do Give, Grant, Make, Ordain, Conſtitute, Declare, Appoint, and Eſtabliſh, That the ſaid <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> And all and every other Perſon and Perſons, Natives and Foreigners, Bodies Poli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tick or Corporate, who, over and above the Perſons before eſpecially Named, have at any time or times before the making of theſe Preſents, Subſcribed and Contributed any Sum or Sums of Money towards the ſaid Sum of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> purſuant to the ſaid Act, and Our ſaid Commiſſion, and have paid the Fourth Part thereof upon their ſaid Subſcriptions, and who are now Living or Exiſtent, and have not Aſſigned their Intereſt in the ſaid Subſcriptions; And all and every the Heirs and Succeſſors of any of the ſaid Original Subſcribers, who are now Dead, and have not in their Life-times Aſſigned their Intereſts in the ſaid Subſcriptions, and the Heirs and Succeſſors of ſuch of the ſaid Aſſignees who are now Dead, and did not in their Life-times Aſſign or Depart with their Intereſt in the ſaid Stock and Annual Fund, and all and every Perſon and Perſons, Natives or Foreigners, Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:31398:4"/>Politick and Corporate, who, either as Original Subſcribers of the ſaid Sum of, <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> and not having parted with their Intereſts in their Subſcriptions, or as Heirs, Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors or Aſſigns, or by any other lawful Title derived, or to be derived from, by, or under the ſaid Original Subſcribers of the ſaid Sum of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> or any of them now have, or at any time or times hereafter ſhall have, or be Intitled to any Part, Share, or Intereſt of, or in the Principal or Capital Stock of the ſaid Corporation, or the ſaid Yearly Fund of One Hundred Thouſand Pounds, granted by the ſaid Act of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, or any Part thereof, ſo long as they reſpectively ſhall have any ſuch Part, Share, or Intereſt therein, ſhall be, and be called one Body Politick and Corporate of themſelves, in Deed and in Name, by the Name of <hi>The Governor and Company of the Bank of</hi> England; and Them by that Name, one Body Politick and Corporate in Deed and in Name, We do, for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, Make, Create, Erect, Eſtabliſh, and Confirm for ever, by theſe Preſents, and by the ſame Name, They and their Succeſſors ſhall have perpetual Succeſſion, and ſhall, and may have and uſe a Common Seal,<note place="margin">May have a Common Seal.</note> for the Uſe, Buſineſs, or Affairs of the ſaid Body Politick and Corporate, and their Succeſſors, with Power to Break, Alter, and to Make a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>new their Seal from time to time at their Pleaſure, and as they ſhall ſee Cauſe. And by the ſame Name,<note place="margin">May Purchaſe and Hold.</note> they and their Succeſſors in all times coming, ſhall be Able and Capable in Law, to Have, Take, Purchaſe, Receive, Hold, Keep, Poſſeſs, Enjoy and Retain to them and their Succeſſors, any Mannors, Meſſuages, Lands, Rents, Tenements, Liberties, Priviledges, Franchiſes, Hereditaments, and Poſſeſſions what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever, and of what Kind, Nature, or Quality ſoever; and moreover to Purchaſe and acquire all Goods and Chattels whatſoever, wherein they are not reſtrained by the ſaid Act. And alſo to Sell, Grant, Demiſe, Alien, or Diſpoſe of the ſame Mannors, Meſſuages, Lands, Rents, Tenements, Priviledges, Franchiſes, Hereditaments, Poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſions, Goods and Chattels,<note place="margin">Sue and be Sued.</note> or any of them. And by the ſame Name, they and their Succeſſors ſhall, and may Sue and Implead, and be Sued and Impleaded, Anſwer and Defend, and be Anſwered and Defended in Courts of Record, or any other Place whatſoever, and before whatſoever Judges, Juſtices, Officers and Miniſters of Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors; and in all and ſingular Pleas, Actions, Suits, Cauſes, and Demands whatſoever, of what Kind, Nature or Sort ſoever, and in as large, ample, and beneficial Manner and Form as any other Body Politick and Corporate, or any other the Liege People of <hi>England,</hi> or other Our Dominions, being Perſons Able and Capable in Law, may, or can Have, Take, Purchaſe, Receive, Hold, Keep, Poſſeſs, Enjoy, Sell, Grant, Demiſe, Alien, Diſpoſe, Sue, Implead, Defend, or An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer, or be Sued, Impleaded, Defended or Anſwered in any manner of wiſe, and ſhall, and may do, and Execute all and ſingular other Matters and Things by the Name aforeſaid, that to them ſhall, or may appertain to do, by Vertue of the ſaid Act or otherwiſe;<note place="margin">Subject to Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demption.</note>
            </p>
            <p>Subject nevertheleſs to the Proviſo and Condition of Redemption in the ſaid Act mentioned. And to all and every other Clauſes, Proviſoes and Conditions in the ſaid Act contained.<note place="margin">Subſcribers and Aſſigns ſhall be Members of the Incorporation.</note>
            </p>
            <p>And we do hereby declare, that all Perſons, having any Intereſt or Part in the Capi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tal Stock or Fund of the ſaid Corporation, either as Original Subſcribers, or by Aſſign<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, or as Heirs, or otherwiſe, ſhall be, and be eſteemed Members of the ſaid Corpora<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, and ſhall be admitted into the ſame without any Fee or Charge whatſoever.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Subſcription Money called Stock.</note>And We do hereby, for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, declare, limit, direct and appoint, that the aforeſaid Sum of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> ſo ſubſcribed as aforeſaid, ſhall be, and be called, accepted, eſteemed, reputed and taken, <hi>The Common, Capital, and Principal Stock of the Corporation hereby Conſtituted.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Subſcribers to be intereſted in the Stock and Fund.</note>And all and every Perſon and Perſons, his, her, and their Heirs, Succeſſors and Aſſigns, according, and in proportion to the Sum or Sums of Money by him, her, or them reſpectively ſubſcribed as aforeſaid, ſhall have, and be deemed to have an Intereſt or Share in the ſaid Principal Stock, and of, and in the Yearly Fund of One Hundred Thouſand Pounds, granted by the ſaid Act of Parliament.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Directions to the Treaſury.</note>And We do hereby, for Us, Our Heirs and Suceſſors, authoriſe, enjoyn, and require the Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury, and Under Treaſurer of Our <hi>Exchequer</hi> now being, and the High Treaſurer, Commiſſioners of the Treaſury, and Under Treaſurer of Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors for the time being, without any fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, or other Warrant to be had, or obtained from Us, Our Heirs, or Succeſſors
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:31398:4"/>to direct their Warrants and Orders, according to the ſaid Act, for the Payment of the yearly Sum of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> by, and out of the Five Seventh Parts (the whole into ſeven equal Parts to be divided) of the Moneys ariſing by the Rates and Duties granted by the ſaid Act, and thereby appointed to be kept apart for the Payment of the ſaid Year<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Fund of One Hundred Thouſand Pounds to the ſaid Governor and Company of the Bank of <hi>England,</hi> and their Succeſſors for ever, under and ſubject nevertheleſs to the Payment of the Iſſues, Fines, Amerciaments and Debts upon Judgments againſt the ſaid Corporation, according to the Purport of the ſaid Act. The firſt Year to be reckoned to begin from the firſt day of <hi>June,</hi> in the Year of Our Lord Chriſt, One Thouſand Six Hundred Ninety and Four. And We do hereby direct and enjoyn the Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury, and the Treaſurer, Commiſſioners of the Treaſury, and Under Treaſurer of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> and the Auditor of the Receipt of Our <hi>Exchequer,</hi> and all other the Officers of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> of Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, now, and for the time being, from time to time, to Iſſue and Pay the ſaid Five Seventh Parts of the Moneys ariſing by the Duties granted by the ſaid Act, or ſo much thereof as ſhall be ſufficient for this purpoſe, to the ſaid Governor and Company of the Bank of <hi>England,</hi> and their Succeſſors, by Weekly Payments, or otherwiſe, as the ſame, or any Part thereof, ſhall from time to time come into the Receipt of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> for, and towards Satisfaction of the ſaid Yearly Sum of</p>
            <p>And in caſe five Seventh Parts of the Weekly Payments in the ſaid Act mentioned, and intended to be the Yearly Fund for the Recompence of the ſaid Subſcribers ſhall not amount unto ſo much as the yearly Sum of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> which is the Annual Fund thereby eſtabliſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed for the ſaid Corporation to Receive. Then We do hereby, for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, Grant, and Agree to, and with the ſaid Governor and Company, and their Succeſſors, that Five Seventh Parts of the ſaid Weekly Moneys or Payments, ſo far as the ſame will extend, ſhall be part of the ſaid Yearly Fund of</p>
            <p>And in caſe the ſaid Duties, by the ſaid Act granted, or any of them, ſhall at any time or times appear to be ſo deficient or low in the Produce of the ſame, as that within any one Year, to be reckoned from the firſt Day of <hi>June,</hi> as aforeſaid, Five Seventh Parts of the Weekly Payments upon the ſame Rates and Duties, or any of them, ſhall not amount to ſo much as <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> within, or for the ſame Year reſpectively, That then, and ſo often, and in every ſuch Caſe, We do hereby authoriſe, enjoyn and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire the Commiſſioners of Our Treaſury, and the Under Treaſurer of the <hi>Exchequer</hi> now being, and the Treaſurer and Under Treaſurer of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> or Commiſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners of the Treaſury for the time being, of Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, forth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with, and without any further or other Warrant to be ſued for, had, or obtained from Us, our Heirs, and Succeſſors in that behalf, to cauſe every ſuch Deficiency to be made good, by applying, iſſuing, or paying ſo much of any Treaſure or Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venue, belonging, or to belong to Us, Our Heirs, or Succeſſors (not being appro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priated to any particular Uſe or Uſes by any Act or Acts of Parliament) towards the Diſcharging or Paying of the ſaid Yearly Fund of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> as together with Five Seventh Parts of the Moneys which ſhall have been brought into the Receipt of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> of, or for the ſaid ſeveral Rates or Duties by the ſaid Act granted, ſhall be ſufficient to Pay off and Diſcharge, and ſhall compleatly Pay off and Diſcharge the ſaid Yearly Fund of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> according to the true Intent and Meaning of the ſaid Act, and of theſe Preſents.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">The Conſtituti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany.</note>And for the better ordering, managing, and governing the Stock and other Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fairs of the ſaid Corporation, and for the Making and Eſtabliſhing a continual Succeſſion of Perſons to be Governor, Deputy Governor, and Directors of the ſaid Corporation. We do by theſe Preſents, for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, grant unto the ſaid Governor and Company of the Bank of <hi>England,</hi> and their Succeſſors, and do hereby ordain and appoint, that there ſhall be from time to time, for ever (of the Members of the ſaid Company) a Governor, a Deputy Governor, and Twenty Four Directors of, and in the ſaid Corporation; which Governor, Deputy Governor, and Directors, or any Thirteen or more of them (of which the Governor or Deputy Governor to be always One) ſhall be, and be called, a Court of Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectors
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:31398:5"/>for the Ordering, Managing and Directing the Affairs of the ſaid Corpora<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, and ſhall have ſuch Powers and Priviledges as are herein after mentioned.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Firſt Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor.</note>And we do hereby Nominate, Conſtitute, Ordain and Appoint, That <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> who is choſen for this Purpoſe by a Majority of the ſaid Subſcribers, <hi>having Five Hundred Pounds</hi> each in the ſaid Capital Stock, purſuant to certain Clauſes in our ſaid Commiſſion contained, ſhall be the Preſent, and Firſt Governor.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Firſt Deputy Governor.</note>And that <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> who is choſen in like manner, ſhall be the Preſent, and Firſt Deputy Governor.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Firſt Twenty Four Directors.</note>And that <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> who are ſeverally choſen in like manner by a Majority of like Subſcribers, ſhall be the Preſent, and Firſt Directors of the ſaid Corporation.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Continuance in their Offices.</note>And the ſaid Governor, Deputy Governor, and Directors, ſhall continue in their reſpective Offices untill the Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>March,</hi> which ſhall be in the Year of Our Lord, One Thouſand, Six Hundred, Ninety Six, and untill others ſhall be duly choſen in their reſpective Offices, and Sworn into the ſame, unleſs they, or any of them ſhall ſooner dye, or be removed, as is herein after mentioned.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Power to Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſemble.</note>And We do further by theſe Preſents, for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, Give and Grant unto the ſaid Governor and Company of the Bank of <hi>England:</hi> And We do hereby Ordain, Will and Appoint, that it ſhall, and may be lawful to, and for all and every the Members of the ſaid Corporation, or Body Politick from time to time to Aſſemble and Meet together at any convenient Place or Places for the Choice of their Governor, Deputy Governor and Directors, and for the Making of By-Laws, Ordinances, Rules, Orders, or Directions for the Government of the ſaid Corporation, and for any other Affairs or Buſineſs concerning the ſame, Publick Notice thereof being firſt given by Writing to be affixed upon the <hi>Royal Exchange</hi> in <hi>London,</hi>
               <note place="margin">Notice of Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Courts.</note> two Days at leaſt before the Time appointed for ſuch Meeting.</p>
            <p>And that all the Members of the ſaid Corporation, or ſo many of them as ſhall be ſo aſſembled, ſhall be, and be called, a General Court of the ſaid Corporation, which Court ſhall Meet and Aſſemble at ſuch Times, and in ſuch Manner as herein after is directed.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Election of ſuc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor, Deputy Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernor, and Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectors.</note>And that all ſucceeding Governors, Deputy Governors, and Directors of the ſaid Corporation, ſhall from, and after the Five and Twentieth Day of March, in the Year of Our Lord, One Thouſand Six Hundred, Ninety Six, be yearly and ſucceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſively Choſen for ever, out of the Members of the ſaid Corporation, on ſome Day or Days, or Times, between the Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>March,</hi> and the Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>April</hi> in each Year, by the Majority of Votes, of all and every the Members of the ſaid Corporation, having then each of them Five Hundred Pounds or more Share or Intereſt in the ſaid Capital Stock and Fund of the ſaid Corporation, and who ſhall be perſonally preſent at ſuch Elections, each of them to have and give one Vote and no more; which ſucceeding Governors, Deputy Governors and Directors ſo Choſen, ſhall ſeverally and reſpectively continue in their reſpective Offices to which they ſhall be ſeverally Elected for one Year, and till others ſhall be duly Choſen and Sworn into their Places reſpectively.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">In Caſe of Death.</note>Provided nevertheleſs, that in caſe of Death, Avoidance, or Removal of the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernor, Deputy Governor, or any of the Directors of the ſaid Corporation for the Time being, the Survivors of them, or the Majority of thoſe remaining in their Office, ſhall, and may at any time Aſſemble together the Members of the ſaid Corporatio, in order to Elect other Perſons, By-Members, qualified to Vote in man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner aforeſaid, in the Room of thoſe then Dead, Removed, or avoided; and that every Deputy Governor (in the Abſence of the Governor) ſhall have the ſame Power as a Governor.<note place="margin">Governor ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent.</note>
            </p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Qualification of Elector.</note>Provided nevertheleſs, and We do hereby Will and Ordain, Conſtitute, Appoint, and Command, that no Perſon or Perſons ſhall be, or be eſteemed, quantified, or ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pable to be an Elector to Vote, or ſhall give any Vote at any General Court, or
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:31398:5"/>otherwiſe for an Election of Governor, Deputy-Governor or Directors, or any of them, or for or concerning the making of By-Laws, or in any other matters re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lating to the Affairs or Government of the ſaid Corporation, who ſhall not at the time of ſuch General Court, have in his, her, or their Name, and Right, and for his, her, or their own Uſe and not in Truſt for any other, Five hundred Pounds or more, Share or Intereſt in the ſaid Capital Stock of the ſaid Corporation: And who alſo ſhall not at the time of holding any ſuch General Court, take the Oath hereafter mentioned, if required thereunto by any Member or Members of the ſaid Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poration then preſent, having each Five hundred Pounds Share or Intereſt, at leaſt, in the ſaid Capital Stock, before the Governor, or Deputy-Governor, or any two or more of the Directors of the ſaid Corporation, <hi>viz. I</hi> A. B. <hi>do Swear,</hi>
               <note place="margin">Oath of Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctors.</note> 
               <hi>that the Sum of Five hundred Pounds or more, of the Capital Stock of the Body-Politique, called by the name of the Governor and Company of the Bank of</hi> England, <hi>doth at this time belong to me in my own Right, and not in Truſt, for any other Perſon or Perſons whatſoever.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">None to have above one Vote.</note>And We do hereby Conſtitute, Ordain, and Appoint, That no one Member of the ſaid Corporation, ſhall in any Election of Governor, Deputy-Governor, Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rector or other Officer of the ſaid Corporation, or in any the Buſineſs or Affairs of the ſaid Corporation, have, or give, any more than one Vote, whatever his Share or Intereſt in the ſaid Capital Stock ſhall be.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Proviſo for Quakers.</note>Provided nevertheleſs, That any Perſon or Perſons, commonly called or known to be Quakers, who at the time of holding ſuch General Court, as aforeſaid, ſhall have Five hundred-Pounds Intereſt or Share, or more in the ſaid Capital Stock, and ſhall then (if thereunto Required by any Member or Members of the ſaid Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poration then preſent, having each Five hundred Pounds Share or Intereſt at leaſt in the ſaid Capital Stock) make and Sign the following Declaration, to wit, <hi>I</hi> A. B. <hi>do ſincerely and ſolemnly Declare in the preſence of God, That the Sum of Five hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Pounds or more of the Capital Stock of the Body Politique, called by the name of the Governor and Company of the Bank of</hi> England, <hi>doth at this time belong to me in my own Right, and not in truſt for any other Perſon or Perſons whatſoever,</hi> ſhall be Capable of having a Vote at any General Court of the ſaid Corporation.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Power to Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſter the Oaths and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claration to Electors.</note>And we do by theſe Preſents, for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, give full Power and Authority, to the Governor, or Deputy-Governor, or any two or more of the Directors of the ſaid Corporation for the time being, to give and Adminiſter the ſaid Oath and Declaration to the ſaid Members: And do hereby Order and Direct them to Adminiſter the ſame accordingly: Provided farther,</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Qualification of Governor.</note>And we do hereby for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, Conſtitute, Ordain, and Appoint, that no Perſon ſhall at any time be capable of being Choſen a Governor of the ſaid Corporation, unleſs he ſhall at the time of ſuch Election, be a Natu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral born Subject of <hi>England,</hi> or Naturalized; and ſhall alſo then have in his own Name, in his own Right, and for his own Uſe, Four thouſand Pounds or more, in the Capital Stock of the ſaid Corporation.</p>
            <p>And that no Perſon ſhall at any time be capable of being choſen Deputy-Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor of the ſaid Corporation,<note place="margin">Qualification of Deputy-Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor.</note> unleſs he ſhall at the time of ſuch Election, be a Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tural born Subject of <hi>England,</hi> or Naturaliz'd, and ſhall alſo then have in his own Name, in his own Right, and for his own Uſe, Three thouſand Pounds or more in the Capital Stock of the ſaid Corporation.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Qualification of Directors.</note>And that no Perſon ſhall be capable of being choſen a Director of the ſaid Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poration, who ſhall not at the time of ſuch Choice be a Natural born Subject of <hi>England,</hi> or Naturalized: And ſhall alſo then have in his own Name, in his own Right, and for his own Uſe, Two thouſand Pounds or more in the ſaid Capital Stock.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Office vacant by leſſening Stock.</note>And that no Governor, Deputy-Governor, or Directors, ſhall continue in his or their reſpective Offices, longer than the continuance of ſuch their reſpective Intereſts and Stocks, in their own Names and Rights, and to their own Uſes reſpectively: But upon parting with, or reducing, his or their reſpective Share, or Intereſt in the ſaid Capital Stock, to any leſſer Sum or Sums than as aforeſaid, the ſaid reſpective Offices or Places of ſuch Governor, Deputy-Governor, or Directors, ſo parting with, reducing, or diminiſhing their ſaid Shares, or Intereſts, as aforeſaid, ſhall Ceaſe, Determine, and become Vacant, and others to be choſen in their rooms, by a general Court of the ſaid Corporation.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Oaths to be taken by Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernors.</note>Provided alſo, and We do by theſe Preſents, for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, Will, Ordain, and Appoint that the ſaid
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:31398:6"/>hereby Nominated to be the firſt Governor, or any Perſon hereafter to be Choſen to the ſaid Office or Truſt of Governor of the ſaid Corporation, ſhall not be capable of Executing or Acting in the ſaid Office or truſt of Governor at any time, until he reſpectively ſhall have taken the Oaths, appointed to be taken by an Act made in the Firſt Year of Our Reign,<note place="margin">Oath of Alle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giance.</note> Entituled, <hi>An Act for the Abrogating of the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance, and appointing other Oaths,</hi> and ſhall not be capable of Executing of, or Acting in the ſaid Office or Truſt of Governor, at any time or times hereafter, until he reſpectively ſhall have taken the Corporal Oath following, To wit,<note place="margin">Oath for Stock.</note> 
               <hi>I</hi> A. B. <hi>do Swear, that the Sum of Four thouſand Pounds of the Capital Stock of the Body Politique, called by the name of the Governor and Company of the Bank of</hi> England, <hi>whereof I am Appointed or Elected to be Governor, doth at this time belong to me in my own Right, and not in truſt for any other Perſon or Perſons whatſoever:</hi> And likewiſe another Oath in the form, or to the effect following, That is to ſay, <hi>I</hi> A. B. <hi>being Nomi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nated or Elected to be Governor of the Company of the Bank of</hi> England,<note place="margin">Oath to the Company.</note> 
               <hi>do Promiſe, and Swear, That I will to the utmoſt of my Power by all Lawful ways and means endeavour to Support and Maintain the Body-Politique, or Fellowſhip of the Governor and Company of the Bank of</hi> England, <hi>and the Liberties and Privileges thereof: And that in the Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the ſaid Office of Governor, I will Faithfully and Honeſtly demean my ſelf, according to the beſt of my Skil and Underſtanding: So help me God.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Oaths to firſt Governor, to be Admini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stred by the Lord Keeper, Chancellor of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> Chief-Baron. Oath to ſuc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors. How Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ministred.</note>And to any future Governor, ſhall and may be Adminiſtred by the Chancellor of <hi>England,</hi> or Keeper of the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> or by the Chancellor of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> or Chief Baron of the Court of <hi>Exchequer,</hi> of Us, Our Heirs, or Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors, for the time being, or by the Governor, or Deputy-Governor of the ſaid Corporation, for the laſt preceding Year; Or (in caſe a Deputy-Governor ſhall be then Sworn into his Office) then by ſuch Deputy-Governor. And We do hereby, for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, Direct, Authorize, and Appoint the Chancel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lor of <hi>England,</hi> and Keeper of the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> Chancellor of the <hi>Exche<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quer,</hi> and Chief Baron of the Court of <hi>Exchequer,</hi> or any of them for the time be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, or ſuch preceding Governor, or preceding Deputy-Governor, or ſuch Deputy-Governor, ſo qualified, as aforeſaid, to Adminiſter the ſaid Oaths to every or any ſuch Perſon Appointed or Elected to be Governor of the ſaid Corporation, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid.</p>
            <p>Provided alſo, and We do hereby for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, Will, and Ordain,<note place="margin">The like Oaths for the Deputy-Governor.</note> and Appoint, that the ſaid <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> hereby Nominated, Conſtituted, and Appointed to be the firſt Deputy-Governor, or any Perſon hereafter to be choſen to the Office or Truſt of Deputy-Governor of the ſaid Corporation, ſhall not be capable of Executing or Acting in the ſaid Office or Truſt of Deputy-Governor, until he ſhall have taken the like Oaths <hi>(mutatis mutandis)</hi> as are before preſcribed to be taken by the Governor.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">How Admini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stred.</note>Which Oaths to the firſt Deputy-Governor, above-named ſhall and may be Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſtred by the Keeper of Our Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> or by the Chancellor of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> or Chief Baron of the Court of <hi>Exchequer,</hi> or by the firſt Governor of the ſaid Corporation, after himſelf ſhall be firſt Sworn, as aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Oath to ſuccee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding Deputy-Governors. How Administred.</note>And to any future Deputy-Governor, ſhall and may be Adminiſtred by the Chan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cellor of <hi>England,</hi> or Keeper of the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> or by the Chancellor of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> or Chief Baron of the Court of <hi>Exchequer,</hi> of Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, for the time being, or by the Governor, or Deputy-Governor of the ſaid Corporation, for the preceding Year: And they are hereby reſpectively Authorized and Directed to Adminiſter the ſaid Oaths to any Deputy-Governor accordingly.</p>
            <p>Provided alſo, And We do by theſe Preſents, for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, Will, and Ordain, and Appoint, That none of the ſaid
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:31398:6"/>hereby Nominated, Conſtituted and Appointed to be the firſt Twenty four Directors of the ſaid Corporation, or any other Perſon or Perſons hereafter to be choſen to the Office or Truſt of a Director of the ſaid Corporation,<note place="margin">Oath of Dire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctors.</note> ſhall be capable to Execute or Act in the ſaid Office of a Director, until he or they ſhall reſpectively have taken the Oaths Mentioned and Appointed in and by one Act made in the Firſt Year of Our Reign, Intituled, <hi>An Act for the Abrogating of the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance, and Appointing other Oaths,</hi>
               <note place="margin">Oath of Alle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giance.</note> nor ſhall be capable to Execute or Act in the ſaid Office or Truſt of a Director, at any time or times hereafter, until he or they reſpectively ſhall have taken the Corporal Oath following, to wit,<note place="margin">Oath for Stocks.</note> 
               <hi>I</hi> A. B. <hi>do Swear, that the Sum of Two thouſand Pounds of the Capital Stock of the Body-Poli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tique, called by the Name of the Governor and Company of the Bank of</hi> England, <hi>whereof I am Appointed or Elected to be a Director, doth at this time belong to me; in my own Right, and not in truſt for any other Perſon or Perſons whatſoever.</hi> And likewiſe another Oath, in the form, or to the effect following,<note place="margin">Oath to the Company.</note> 
               <hi>viz. I</hi> A. B. <hi>do Swear, that in the Office of a Director of the Corporation or Company of the Bank of</hi> England, <hi>I will be indifferent and equal to all manner of Perſons: And I will give my beſt Advice and Aſſiſtance, for the ſupport and good Government of the ſaid Corporation. And in the Execution of the ſaid Office of Director, I will faithfully and honeſtly demean my ſelf, according to the beſt of my Skil and Underſtanding: So help me God.</hi> Which Oaths to the firſt Twenty Four Directors herein Nominated,<note place="margin">How Admini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stred to the firſt Directors.</note> and every of them reſpectively ſhall and may be Adminiſtred by the ſaid Keeper of Our Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> or by the Chancellor of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> or Chief Baron of Our Court of <hi>Exchequer,</hi> or by the firſt Governor or Deputy-Governor herein before Named, ſo as ſuch firſt Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernor, or Deputy-Governor, (in caſe they or either of them, do Adminiſter the ſaid Oaths, to the ſaid Directors or any of them) be firſt Sworn, as is before-men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Oath to ſuccee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding Directors, how Admini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stred.</note>And the ſaid Oaths, to any future Director and Directors, ſhall and may be Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſtred by the Chancellor of <hi>England,</hi> or Keeper of the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> or by the Chancellor of the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> or Chief Baron of the Court of <hi>Exchequer,</hi> of Us, Our Heirs, or Succeſſors, for the time being, or any of them, or by a Sworn Governor, or Deputy-Governor of the ſaid Corporation for the time being, or by the Governor or Deputy-Governor for the preceding year: And they are here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by Authorized and Required, to Adminiſter the ſaid Oaths to all and every ſuch Director and Directors, from time to time accordingly.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Oath of Ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctors.</note>Provided alſo, and We do by theſe Preſents for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Will, Ordain, and Appoint, that all and every the other Members of the ſaid Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poration, having each Five Hundred Pounds or more Intereſt, or Share, in the Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pital Stock of the ſaid Corporation, before he or they ſeverally ſhall be capable to give any Vote in any General Court to be held for the ſaid Corporation, ſhall take the ſaid Oaths appointed, in, and by the ſaid Act of Parliament made in the firſt year of Our Reign, Intituled,<note place="margin">Oath of Alle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giance. How Admini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stred.</note> 
               <hi>An Act for the Abrogating of the Oaths of Supremacy and Allegiance, and appointing other Oaths,</hi> before the ſaid Governor or Deputy-Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor of the ſaid Corporation, for the time being, who are hereby reſpectively Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thoriſed to Adminiſter the ſame; And alſo the Oath in the Words, or to the effect following, that is to ſay,<note place="margin">Oath to the Company.</note> 
               <hi>J. A. B. Do Swear that I will be Faithful to the Governor and Company of the Bank of</hi> England, <hi>whereof I am a Member; and in all General Courts, when, and as often as I ſhall be preſent, will, according to the beſt of my Skill and Under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding, give my Advice, Counſel, and Aſſiſtance, for the ſupport and good Government of the ſaid Corporation; ſo help me God.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Proviſo for Quakirs.</note>Provided nevertheleſs that any Perſon or Perſons, commonly called or known to be Quakers, having each Five Hundred Pounds, or more Intereſt, or Share, in the Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pital Stock of the ſaid Corporation, before they ſhall be capable of Voting in any ſuch General Court as aforeſaid, ſhall and may inſtead of the Oaths hereby preſcribed to be taken by the reſpective Members, having each Five Hundred Pounds or more, as aforeſaid) before the ſaid Governor or Deputy-Governors, ſolemnly Promiſe and Declare, as in the preſence of God in Words, or to the ſame effect, <hi>(Mutatis Mutandis)</hi> with the ſaid Oath laſt herein preſcribed to be taken by the Members of the ſaid Corporation, having Five Hundred Pounds or more Intereſt, or Share, in the Capi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tal Stock of the ſaid Corporation, and ſhall ſeverally Subſcribe the ſame, together with the Declaration appointed for ſuch Diſſenters as ſcruple to take Oaths, by ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Act made in the firſt year of our Reign, Intituled, <hi>An Act for Exempting Their Majeſties Proteſtant Subjects, Diſſenting from the Church of</hi> England, <hi>from the Penalties of certain Laws;</hi> which Declarations and Subſcriptions, the ſaid Governor and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puty
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:31398:7"/>Governor for the time being, or either of them are hereby Impowered and Required, to take and Adminiſter.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Power to Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſter Oaths to Officers.</note>And furthermore, Our Will and Pleaſure is, and We do hereby, for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Ordain and Appoint, That the ſaid Court of Directors ſhall have Power and Authority to Adminiſter an Oath to all the Inferiour Agents or Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants, that ſhall be employed in the Service of the ſaid Corporation, for the Faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful and due Execution of their ſeveral Places and Truſts in them Repoſed, in the Words,<note place="margin">Oath to Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers.</note> or to the effect following, that is to ſay; <hi>J. A. B. being Elected into the Office or place of Treaſurer, to the Governor and Company of the Bank of</hi> England, <hi>do Swear, that I will be True and Faithful to the ſaid Governor and Company, and will faithfully and truely Execute and Diſcharge the ſaid Office, or place of Treaſurer, to the utmoſt of my Skill and Power; ſo help me God:</hi> And the like Oath to the other Agents and Servants, <hi>Mutatis Mutandis.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Neglect or Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſal of Oaths.</note>And in caſe any Perſon hereby Nominated, or hereafter to be Elected, Governor, Deputy-Governor, or Director, as aforeſaid, ſhall for the ſpace of Ten days, after ſuch Nomination or Election, neglect or refuſe to take the reſpective Oaths hereby appointed to be taken as aforeſaid, or ſhall refuſe or neglect to take upon him, his, or their Offices, that then and in every ſuch Caſe, the Office and Place of every ſuch Perſon ſo neglecting or refuſing, ſhall become vacant, and others be choſen in their Places by a General Court of the ſaid Corporation.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Dividends how made.</note>And We do hereby further Will and Appoint, That no Dividend ſhall at any time be made by the ſaid Governor and Company, ſave only out of the Intereſt, Profit, or Produce ariſing by, or our of the ſaid Capital Stock, or Fond, or by ſuch Deal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, Buying, or Selling, as is allowed by the ſaid Act of Parliament, until Redem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ption by Parliament, of the ſaid yearly Fund of One Hundred Thouſand Pounds; And that no Dividend whatſoever, ſhall at any time be made without the Conſent of the Members of the ſaid Corporation, in a General Court qualified, to Vote as aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Four General Courts every year.</note>And We do hereby Will and Appoint, that the ſaid Governor, or in his Abſence, the Deputy Governor for the time being, ſhall from time to time, and are hereby Required, upon ſuch notice to be given as aforeſaid, to Summon and Appoint Four General Courts at leaſt in every year, whereof one to be in the month of <hi>September,</hi> another in the Month of <hi>December,</hi> another in the Month of <hi>April,</hi> and another in the Month of <hi>July;</hi> And we do further Will and Appoint, that if at any time or times, there ſhall be a failure of holding a General Court in any of the ſaid Months, by the default of the Governor, and Deputy-Governor, or either of them, that then, and ſo often, and in every ſuch caſe, any three or more of the Directors of the ſaid Corporation, ſhall and may Summon and call a General Court, which ſhall meet and be holden in the Month next coming after the Month in which the ſame ſhould have been holden upon the Summons of the Governor or Deputy-Governor, as aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>And moreover, We do by theſe Preſents Will, Direct and Appoint, that the ſaid Governor, or in his abſence the Deputy-Governor, for the time being, ſhall from time to time, upon Demand to be made, by any Nine or more of the ſaid Members, having each of them Five hundred Pounds or more Interſt or Share in the ſaid Capi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tal Stock, within ten Days after ſuch Demand Summon and call ſuch General Courts to be held of the Members of the ſaid Corporation, qualified for Electors, as aforeſaid,<note place="margin">A General Court to be Sum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moned at any time on demand.</note> and in default of the Governor, or Deputy-Governor to Summon and call ſuch Court, it ſhall and may be lawful to and for the ſaid Nine, or more Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers, having each Five hundred Pounds Stock, as aforeſaid, upon ten Days notice in Writing, to be fixed upon the <hi>Royal Exchange</hi> in <hi>London,</hi> to Summon and hold a General Court, and there to do and diſpatch any buſineſs relating to the Government or Affairs of the ſaid Corporation, and to hear and debate any Complaint that ſhall be made againſt any Governor, Deputy-Governor, or Directors, for miſ-manage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of his, or their reſpective Offices.</p>
            <p>And if ſuch Governor, Deputy-Governor, or Directors, ſhall not clear him or themſelves of ſuch Complaint to the ſatisfaction of the Major part of the Members of the ſaid Corporation,<note place="margin">Miſdemeanor of Governor, De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puty Governor, or Directors.</note> in the ſaid General Court aſſembled, That then within ten Days, another General Court ſhall be called and held, as aforeſaid, of the Members of the ſaid Corporation, qualified to Vote, as aforeſaid: Finally, to determine the ſame by the Majority of their Votes, as aforeſaid, who may remove or diſplace all or any the ſaid Governor, Deputy-Governor, and Directors, for ſuch Miſdemeanors or Abuſe of their Offices, and Elect and Choſe others in his or their rooms, in the
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:31398:7"/>ſame manner, as the ſaid Elections between the Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>March,</hi> and the Five and Twentieth Day of <hi>April,</hi> are herein before directed to be made.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">In caſe of Death of Governor, Deputy-Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor or Directors.</note>And in every caſe, where any Governor, Deputy-Governor, or Directors, ſhall happen to dye or be removed, or his Office ſhall otherwiſe become void before the Expiration of the time, for which he ſhall have been Elected, the Major part of the Members of the ſaid Corporation to be Aſſembled in a General Court, and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing qualified as aforeſaid, ſhall and may Elect and Chooſe any other Member or Members of the ſaid Corporation, qualified as aforeſaid, into the Office of ſuch Governor, Deputy-Governor, or Director, that ſhall ſo Die, or be removed, or whoſe Office ſhall ſo become void, which Perſon ſo to be choſen ſhall continue in the ſaid Office until the next Uſual time hereby appointed for Election, and until others ſhall be duly Choſen and Sworn.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">How the Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor, Deputy-Governor, Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rectors ſhall Act, and the Power given to them.</note>And for the better Ordering and Managing the Affairs of the ſaid Corporation, We do by theſe Preſents, for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, Grant unto the ſaid Governor and Company of the Bank of <hi>England,</hi> and their Succeſſors: And we do by theſe Preſents, Will, Authorize, and Appoint, That the ſaid Governor, De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puty-Governor and Directors, for the time being, or any Thirteen or more of them, (of which the Governor or Deputy-Governor to be always one) ſhall and may from time to time, and at all convenient times, aſſemble and meet together at any con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venient Place or Places, for the Direction and Management of the affairs and buſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of the ſaid Corporation, and then and there to hold Courts of Directors for the purpoſes aforeſaid, and Summon General Courts to meet as often as they ſhall ſee cauſe. And that the ſaid Governor, Deputy-Governor, and Directors, or the Major part of them ſo aſſembled, (whereof the Governor or Deputy-Governor is to be always one) ſhall and may Act according to ſuch By-Laws, Conſtitutions, Orders, Rules, or Directions, as ſhall from time to time be made and given unto them, by the General Court of the ſaid Corporation: And in all Caſes where ſuch By-Laws, Conſtitutions, Orders, Rules, or Directions, by or from the General Court ſhall be wanting, the ſaid Governor, Deputy-Governor, and Directors, or the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jor part of them ſo Aſſembled, whereof the Governor, or Deputy-Governor is to be always one, ſhall and may direct and manage all the Affairs and Buſineſs of the ſaid Corporation, in the borrowing or receiving of Moneys, and giving Security for the ſame, under the Common Seal of the ſaid Corporation: And in their deal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in Bills of Exchange, or the buying or ſelling of <hi>Bullion</hi> Gold or Silver, or in ſelling any Goods, Wares, or Merchandizes whatſoever, which ſhall really and <hi>Bona Fide</hi> be left or depoſited with the ſaid Corporation, for Money Lent and Advanced there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and which ſhall not be redeemed at the time agreed, or within three Months after, and in ſelling ſuch Goods, as ſhall or may be the produce of Lands, purchas'd by the ſaid Corporation, or in the lending or advancing any of the Moneys of the ſaid Corporation, and taking Pawns or other Securities for the ſame: And to chooſe and appoint the Agents or Servants which ſhall from time to time be neceſſary to be employed in the Affairs or buſineſs of the ſaid Corporation, and to allow and pay reaſonable Salleries and Allowances to the ſaid Agents and Servants reſpectively, and them or any of them from time to time to remove or diſplace as they ſhall ſee Cauſe. And Generally to act and do in all matters and things whatſoever, which by the ſaid recited Act of Parliament ſhall or may be done, and in all matters and things whatſoever, which they ſhall Judge neceſſary for the well ordering and ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>naging of the ſaid Corporation, and the Affairs thereof; and to do, enjoy, perform, and execute all the Powers, Authorities, Privileges, Acts, and things, in relation to the ſaid Corporation, as fully to all intents and purpoſes, as if the ſame were done by the Governor and Company of the Bank of <hi>England,</hi> or by a General Court of the ſame; Subject nevertheleſs to ſuch Reſtrictions, Limitations, Rules, or Appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments as are contained in the ſaid recited Act of Parliament, for or concerning the Trade, Buſineſs, or Affairs of the ſaid Corporation, or otherwiſe relating thereunto.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Power to Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Courts to make By-Laws.</note>And We do hereby, for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, give full Power to all and every the ſaid Members qualified for Electors, as aforeſaid, in their General Courts or Aſſemblies, aforeſaid, by Majority of their Votes, as aforeſaid, to make and Conſtitute ſuch By-Laws and Ordinances, for and relating to the Affairs and Government of the ſaid Corporation; and the Impoſing Mulcts and Amerciaments upon Offenders againſt the ſame, as to them ſhall ſeem meet, ſo that ſuch By-Laws be not Repug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant to the Laws of this Our Kingdom, and be Confirmed, and Approved, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the Statutes in ſuch caſe made and provided.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:31398:8"/>
               <note place="margin">Mulcts and A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mercements ſhall be to the uſe of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany.</note>All which Mults and Amerciaments ſhall and may be received and recovered to the only Uſe and Behoof of the ſaid Governor and Company of the Bank of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> and their Succeſſors, without any Account, or other Matter or thing to be therefore rendred to Us, Our Heirs, or Succeſſors.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">General Courts to allow Salle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries to the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernor, Deputy Governors, and Directors.</note>And alſo to allow ſuch Sallaries or Allowances to the ſaid Governor, Deputy-Governor, and Directors, as to them ſhall ſeem meet. And we do hereby for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, Ordain and Appoint, That the firſt General Court for the ſaid Corporation, ſhall be held within the ſpace of Twenty eight days next after the Date of theſe Preſents.<note place="margin">Day of first General Court. Directions for Aſſignment of the Stock and Fund.</note>
            </p>
            <p>Provided always, and for the aſcertaining and limiting how, and in what man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, and under what Rules the ſaid Capital Stock and yearly Fund of 100000 <hi>l.</hi> ſhall and may be Aſſignable and Aſſigned, transferable and transfered by ſuch Perſon and Perſons as ſhall from time to time have any Intereſt or ſhare in the ſame; We do hereby direct and appoint, that there ſhall be conſtantly kept in the publick Office of the ſaid Governor and Company of the Bank of <hi>England,</hi> a Regiſter, or Book or Books, wherein all Aſſignments and Transferrs ſhall be Entred. And We do hereby for Us, Our Heirs and Succeſſors, purſuant, and according to the Power given unto Us, by the ſaid Act of Parliament, Order, Limit, Direct and Appoint; that the method and manner of making all Aſſignments and Transfers of the ſaid Capital Stock, and yearly Fund, or any part thereof, ſhall be by an En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try in the ſaid Book or Books, Signed by the party ſo Aſſigning or Transfering in the Words,<note place="margin">Form of Trans<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer.</note> or to the effect following, <hi>viz.</hi> Memorandum, <hi>That</hi> I. A. B. <hi>this <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                     <desc> _____ </desc>
                  </gap> day of <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                     <desc> _____ </desc>
                  </gap> in the year of Our Lord <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                     <desc> _____ </desc>
                  </gap> do Aſſign and Transferr <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                     <desc> _____ </desc>
                  </gap> of my Intereſt or Share in the Capital Stock and Fund of the Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor and Company of the Bank of</hi> England, <hi>and all Benefit ariſing thereby, unto <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                     <desc> _____ </desc>
                  </gap> his Heirs, Executors and Aſſigns. Witneſs my Hand</hi> 
               <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> Or in caſe the Perſon Aſſigning be not perſonally preſent, then by an Entry in the ſaid Book or Books, Signed by ſome Perſon thereunto lawfully Authorized,<note place="margin">By Letter of Attorney.</note> by Letter of Attorney, or Writing under Hand and Seal, atteſted by Two or more Witneſſes, in the Words, or to the eflect following, <hi>viz.</hi> Memorandum, <hi>That</hi> I A. B. this <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>day of</hi> 
               <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>in the year of our Lord</hi> 
               <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>and</hi> 
               <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>by virtue of a Letter of Attorney,</hi>
               <note place="margin">Form of Trans<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer, by Letter of Attorney.</note> 
               <hi>or Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty under the Hand and Seal of</hi> 
               <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Dated the</hi> 
               <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>day of</hi> 
               <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>in the ſaid year</hi> 
               <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>do in the name, and on the behalfe of the ſaid</hi> 
               <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Aſſign and Transferr</hi> 
               <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>of the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt or Share of the ſaid</hi> 
               <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>in the Capital Stock and Fund of the Governor and Company of the Bank of</hi> England, <hi>and all Benefits ariſing thereby, unto</hi> 
               <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>his Heirs and Aſſigns,</hi>
               <note place="margin">Acceptance.</note> 
               <hi>Witneſs my Hand.</hi> 
               <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> Under which transfer the Perſon or Perſons, Bodies Politick or Corporate, to whom ſuch Aſſignment or Transfer ſhall be made, or ſome other Perſon by him or them lawfully Authorized thereunto, ſhall Sign his or their Name or Names, atteſting that he or they do freely and voluntarily accept of the ſame. And that the Entry Signed, as aforeſaid, and no other way or method ſhall be the manner and method uſed in the Paſſing, Aſſigning, or Transferring the Intereſt or Share in the ſaid Capital Stock or Fund, and ſuch Transfer or Aſſignment ſhall be good and available, and Convey the whole Eſtate, and Intereſt of the Party Transfering, or Ordering the ſame to be Transfered.</p>
            <p>Provided always, that any Perſon having any Share or Intereſt in the ſaid Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pital Stock or Fund,<note place="margin">Diviſeable by Will, attested by <hi>3</hi> Witneſſes. Entry of the Deviſe in the Companies Books Governor or Deputy, (in his abſence) not to Vote in general Courts, unleſs in Caſes of E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quality of Votes</note> may diſpoſe or deviſe the ſame, by his laſt Will and Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtament, atteſted by Three or more credible Witneſſes. But however, that ſuch Deviſee ſhall not Transfer the ſame, or be intituled to receive any Dividend, until an Entry or <hi>Memorandum</hi> of ſo much of the ſaid Will, as relates to the ſaid Stock or Fund, be made in the Book or Books, or ſome other Book or Books to be kept by the ſaid Governor and Company for that purpoſe.</p>
            <p>And We do hereby Will and Appoint, that the ſaid Governor, or in his Abſence, the Deputy-Governor, ſhall not have any Vote in a General Court or Courts of Directors, Save where there ſhall happen to be an Equality, or Equal Number of Votes.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:31398:8"/>Provided nevertheleſs, That all matters and things which the ſaid Governor,<note place="margin">Sub-Commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tees.</note> Deputy-Governor, or Directors, ſhall in manner, as aforeſaid, Order and Direct to be done by Sub-Committees, or other Perſons appointed under them, ſhall and may (by Vertue of ſuch Orders) be done by the ſaid Sub-Committees, or other Perſons ſo appointed.</p>
            <p>And We do for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, Grant and Declare,<note place="margin">Non-obstante.</note> That theſe Our Letters-Patents, or the Inrollment thereof, ſhall be, in and by all things Valid, and Effectual in the Law, according to the true intent and meaning of the ſame; and ſhall be taken, conſtrued, and adjudged in the moſt favourable and beneficial Senſe, for the beſt Advantage of the ſaid Corporation, as well in Our Courts of Record as elſewhere; notwithſtanding any Non-recital, Mis-recital, Defect, In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>certainty, or Imperfection in theſe Our Letters-Patents.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Without Fee in the <hi>Hanaper.</hi>
               </note>And Our Will and Pleaſure is, That theſe Preſents to the Governor and Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny aforeſaid, under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> ſhall be in due manner made and Sealed without Fine or Fee, great or ſmall, to Us in Our <hi>Hanaper,</hi> or elſewhere to Our Uſe therefore, any ways to be rendred, paid, or made.</p>
            <p>
               <note place="margin">Covenant to grant further Power.</note>And We do hereby, for Us, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, Covenant, Grant, and Agree, to and with the ſaid Governor and Company, and their Succeſſors, That We, Our Heirs, and Succeſſors, ſhall and will from time to time, and at all times hereafter, upon the humble Suit and Requeſt of the ſaid Governor and Company, and their Succeſſors, Give and Grant unto them, all ſuch further and other Powers, Privileges, Authorities, Matters, and Things, which we or they can or may law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully grant, and as ſhall be reaſonably adviſed and deſired by the Council learned of the ſaid Governor and Company for the time being, and ſhall be approved by Our Attorney, or Sollicitor-General, on Our behalf. <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> In Witneſs, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <signed>CH<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>TE.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
